## **Umair Liagat**

Junior Flutter Developer

I am Junior Flutter mobile applications developer with proven experience in creating and building Flutter applications, for android and IOS platforms. Strong expertise in building applications with Firebase as a database. Have grip in working on APIs. I posses good problem solving skills



umairliaqat552@gmail.com

0313-4146-206

Lahore, Pakistan

linkedin.com/in/umair-liagat-305450228 in

github.com/Umairliaqat33 (

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelors in Software Engineering - BSSE** University of South Asia - Cantt campus

10/2020 - 06/2024 Lahore

Courses

 Object Oriented Programming

- Software Requirement - S

Specifications

Advance Programming

 Software Project management

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Junior Flutter Developer CYBRNODE

11/2022 - 03/2023 Lahore

That was software house specialized in building web and mobile apps Project Ownership

- I was working solely on a project named as Switch Driver at CYBRNODE.
- Problems with logic: Using my problem solving skill, i created many difficult logics there.
- Track a user's location and showing it on map. I solved it swiftly by adding a small piece of code.

Contact: Umar - umar@cybrnode.com

# **Customer Support Representative Team Lead**Digital Estimating

08/2021 - Present Lahore

This is a construction estimation firm where we help US contractors with bidding process which is before construction.

Team Lead

- Within a short interval of time i had achieved the position of a team lead for CSR department there.
- On call recording: Before i was working there, there was no way to track a call from a client after we answer it. I solved that issue, using a screen recorder and keeping those recordings save.
- Problem to train new hires: When a new employee for the
  position of CSR was hired there was no way to train him then
  giving him real life experience which can cause losing of
  customers, I solved it by storing some important call recordings
  which will help new hire to understand the nature of calls he will
  be receiving.

Contact: HR - 042 38934325

## SKILLS

Flutter Development Google Maps Deep linking

API Integration Firebase Problem solving

Interpersonal Skill Quick learning

Coding Standards UI/UX design Firestore

Debugging Computer Science Provider

Riverpod

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Mera Godamm (11/2023 - 12/2023)

 This is an inventory management application specially developed for Shoes wholesalers, it helps them to keep a record of their inventory and also helps them keep a record of their daily sales instead of keep it on paper.

#### Life Link (03/2024 - 05/2024)

- Developed a comprehensive mobile application, LifeLink, to enhance emergency response and hospital bed management. Key features include.
- Patient Module: One-click ambulance requests during emergencies.
- Ambulance Driver Module: Real-time request notifications and route optimization.
- Hospital Management Module: Real-time bed occupancy updates and efficient resource allocation.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Flutter internship (07/2022 - 10/2022)

I completed my internship in flutter from CYBRNODE. There i got to learn a lot of new things that i had never hear of before. Most important thing I got to learn was code writing style and code formatting.

#### Tech War Mobile app winner (12/2024 - 12/2024)

We joined an inter-university competition to create an **e-commerce** app with a **CART system**. We added an **API** for sample data. Our app met the requirements, offering valuable insights and practical development experience and helped us to **win competetion** 

#### FESTIVASIA 4th edition winner (03/2023 - 03/2023)

A inter-university app development competition was held in our university with the help of Softech society. 4-5 teams were competing in that competition and we were given a small application to build. We won that competition with first position.